Bloodlust: Subspecies III is a horror, fantasy,
thriller film directed by Ted Nicolaou.
Still in the thrall of the evil vampire Radu, Michelle
yearns to be taught the skills of the vampire.
Meanwhile, her sister Becky tries to free her from his evil
clutches, and this time, she's brought some help.
Radu Vladislas, played by Anders Hove.
Michelle Morgan, played by Denice Duff.
Mel, played by Kevin Spirtas.
Rebecca Morgan, played by Melanie Shatner.
Mummy, played by Pamela Gordon.
Lieutenant Marin, played by Ion Haiduc.
Subspecies is a direct-to-video horror film series produced
by Full Moon Studios and Castel Film Studios.
The series ran from 1991 to 2023, and followed the exploits of the vampire Radu Vladislas, portrayed by
Anders Hove, and his efforts to turn Michelle Morgan (Denice Duff) into his fledgling.
A spin-off film, Vampire Journals, was released in 1997, which featured
characters that would go on to appear in the fourth installment.
Ted Nicolaou wrote and directed all six films, including the spin-off.
The series was shot on location in Romania, utilizing stop-motion and rod puppet
techniques to achieve the look the director wanted for the eponymous creatures.
The films have received generally mixed reviews, with critics citing vampire clichés as a downfall, but
generally commending the director's choice to film in Romania, as well as the special effects.
The film explores themes of monster, sibling
relationship, vampire, catacombs, castle.
The tone is dark and intense.